Carey Orr Cartoons
Carey Orr Cartoons
- Cartoons
  - 1916-1928
    - Keep shoving!, 1926; 1926.0057.Orr; A large burglar labeled "Organized Crime" is being backed into a wall by a large spear labeled "Crime & Pardon's probe." Behind him is a man labeled "Guilty politician" with money coming out his pockets and a man labeled "Political crook." They are standing by a barrel filled with money and sacks of money on the ground. The "Guilty Politician" says, "I hope they don't push it too far!"sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Keeping everybody else waiting., 1926; 1926.0058.Orr; Traveling along a road from the U.S. Capitol is a woman. She is labeled "Senate" and has dropped her luggage labeled "Legislation," her purse labeled "Tax Bill Delay" and its contents as she was about to board a street car. The street car is labeled "1926 Business" The Conductor yells, "All Aboard" and he is labeled "Business." Inside the street car is a man labeled "Public." There is a sign that reads "1925 Income tax return."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by the Chicago Tribune." Number "655" written on pencil on upper left recto. " (Oversize 11)
    - The knockout champion., 1926; 1926.0059.Orr; A bulletin board on a building reads: Sparring partners wanted." A large boxer is shown and is labeled "French Financial Problems." Entering the building are men labeled "French Politicians. Exiting the building are beat up boxers labeled "French cabinets."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - The ladies aren't falling for those knights in armor any more., 1926; 1926.0060.Orr; A knight in full armour is labeled "Europe - Militarism - Heavy Armaments." He is surrounded by men with tools trying to fix his armour. They are labeled "Diplomat,"Statesman," and "European disarmament parley." A picture on the wall is labeled "The modern business suit." It shows Uncle Sam being admired by three women labeled "Prosperity,"Progress," and "Commerce."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." Doodle on verso." (Oversize 11)
    - Leave a foot in the door., 1926; 1926.0061.Orr; Uncle Sam is talking to a woman labeled "Europe" just inside a door labeled "America's entrance into European Affairs." Uncle Sam leaves one foot labeled "Reservations" propping the door open. Inside the house is a man labeled "World Court" who says to a man labeled "League of Nations,"Don't start anything until we get him all the way in."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Leaving the word "obey" out of the ceremony.", 1926; 1926.0062.Orr; A bridge labeled "U.S. Senate" is seen with a marriage license that reads "Promise to love, honor and Obey, signed U.S. Senate." Obey has been crossed out of the license. She carries a rolling pin labeled "Reservations" and she says, "I love him, but I don't trust him." In the background to the left are two men who carry a sign "The bridegroom 'World Court' - Best Man 'League of Nations.'" To the right is a minister that is labeled "Simon pure internationalists."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Left out in the rain., 1926; 1926.0063.Orr; A large eagle labeled "U.S. Gov't" has spread wings labeled "Immigration law" and "Tariff protection" over a nest of little baby birds labeled "U.S. Labor" and "U.S. Manufacturing." Caught in a rain storm of "Unsettled world conditions" is a little bird labeled "Farming industry" that is getting drenched."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Let Cal do it", 1926; 1926.0064.Orr; A white cat labeled "Miners" and a black cat labeled "Operators" are tied up on a line labeled "Hard coal tie-up" hanging upside down and fighting. Two men on the ground have been beaten in the fighting, they are "Gov. Pinchot." and "State Politicians." The ground is labeled "Pennsylvania." To the right in the background is a woman labeled "U.S. Senate invitation to Coolidge" signaling to "The President" to come over and look at the fight."sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. "Greece+France+Austria+Germany+Great Britain." Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Life on the frontier., 1926; 1926.0065.Orr; Cartoon in two scenes: Upper scene: A pioneer is shown behind a rock holding up his coonskin cap and waving it to check of the coast is clear. An arrow is flying in the air. Lower scene: A man is walking around a street corner and he props his hat on his umbrella and checks to see if the coast is clear before he goes around the corner. The street is labeled "Chicago." Litter is scattered around the ground and a piece of paper reads "Chicago gangs use machine guns."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay. "Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Liquidating Englands debt., 1926; 1926.0066.Orr; Uncle Sam is pumping a water pump labeled "U.S. Expenditures for Rubber." The hose is labeled "English monopoly on Rubber." on the other side of the globe, "J.B." holds the end of the hose and sprays it into a bucket labeled "Repayment of England's debt to U.S."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Listening to the wrong voice., 1926; 1926.0067.Orr; A man labeled "Europe" sits on a chair holding an ear trumpet to his head. Scattered around him are pieces of paper labeled' "Unpaid debts to U.S. "IOU," and "Debt." A man talks into this horn and says, "Don't you worry- We're going to cancel all your debts and join The League of Nations." The man is labeled "Self appointed representative of America abroad." On a far distant shore is the "Voice of American public opinion" that is saying"Defeat of world -court senators!!!"Debt settlement - No cancellations!"overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - The little boys have taken their toys to bed with them., 1926; 1926.0068.Orr; A mother labeled "Europe" throws her hands in the air as she sees a bed filled with boys and their toys. The bed is labeled "League of Nations," and the boys are: Balkans"Italy,"France" and "England." The toys they have are guns and weapons labeled "Military preparations," and "Militarism." The mother says, "No wonder you children can't go to sleep!"sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Loaded up., 1926; 1926.0069.Orr; Santa Claus stands by a sleigh brimming with presents. He holds his list and says, "Let's see, now, if I've remembered everybody." The reindeer pulling the sleigh is a man labeled "PA."sketches for cartoon on verso. Surface abrasion on verso from tape removal. Torn paper overlay: Copyright, 1926, by The..........." (Oversize 11)
    - The logical way to get rid of them., 1926; 1926.0070.Orr; At the top of a cliff "Sane Citizenry" are pushing a large barrel labeled "Lawful Wines & Beer - Low proof" off the edge. Below are men labeled "Bootleg Ring,"Grafter," and "Crime Growth." They stand amid "Poison Whisky," and"Money enough to corrupt public officials."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Making a hit with the man who pays the bills., 1926; 1926.0071.Orr; A woman posed as an elephant is sitting at a table labeled "Gov't Expenditures." She sits in a chair labeled "Republican Administration." Sitting across from her at the table is a man in a chair labeled "Tax payer." He holds a menu labeled "Reduced income taxes." Uncle Sam is the waiter, and he is labeled "Income tax collector." The man says to the woman, "Er - dear- since you started dieting you look positively beautiful." She is eating from a bowl labeled "Coolidge economy."sketch for cartoon on verso as well as writing down trains of thought of what to put in captions on the cartoon. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - The man who gave us our first riding lesson one hundred and fifty years ago last night., 1926; 1926.0072.Orr; Uncle Sam is riding a horse whose girth is in the shape of the globe and labeled "The world." The saddle is labeled "World Power" and there are bags labeled "Wealth,"Invention,"Industry,"Science," and "Education," hanging from the saddle. In the left foreground is the image of Paul Revere on his horse."Revere's midnight ride was on April 10th, 1775. That would make it the 151st year of his ride if the cartoon was published in 1926. Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso. Torn paper overlay: ...Pat.; Copyri.... The Chicago Tribun...." (Oversize 11)
    - Maybe he's trying to see how many enemies he can make for his country., 1926; 1926.0073.Orr.; A man sits in a chair labeled "Dictator Mussolini" at a desk. He has written a note that says, "Ban on Christmas Trees for German children in Tyrol." Scattered about the desk are newspaper with different headlines. They read: German Newspaper - Bitter criticism sic of Italy over Christmas Tree decree,"American News - Criticism of Italian Gov.'t,"French Newspaper - Bitter Criticism of Fascisti," and "English News - Criticism of Italy." Standing at a window in the background is "Wilhelm II," who says, "That's the way I got my start."doodles for unknown drawing on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Maybe somethings missing., 1926; 1926.0074.Orr; A man is trying to fix an automobile labeled "Europe - wrecked by the War." The man labeled "Statesman" has packages labeled "Foreign trade" and "Business" in the back seat. He is perpendicular to a small bridge that leads the way "To Prosperity." In a small puddle labeled "Loss of Credit," under the bridge is an opened automobile gas tank labeled "Financial gas Tank - Unpaid debts." A railroad crossing sign is labeled "World War - 1914 - 1918."sketches for unknown drawing on verso. "John Bull" Paper overlay: Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Moving the public to vote., 1926; 1926.0075.Orr; In the background is the figure of a man sleeping on a rocking chair labeled "Voter's Disinterest." He is enormous in comparison to the men surrounding him trying to pry the platform he is on towards the "Polling Place." The platform is being moved by barrels of money labeled "Advertising expenses"Organization expenses,"Rentals for halls," and "Big campaign expenses." A man labeled "Politics" stands in the foreground and says, "If anybody knows of a better way of getting him to the polls, I'd like to hear about it."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - A nervous bird., 1926; 1926.0076.Orr; In the background behind a fence, "Mussolini" is sharpening his axe, "Italy," on a grinding stone labeled "Imperialism." Mussolini says, "I'm only going to chop some wood." A pile of wood is labeled, "Development of Italian Resources." In the foreground in another yard, axes labeled "Old Russia,"Greece,"France,"Balkans," and "England," are lying on the ground unused with dull blades. A turkey is in a coop labeled "Turkey" and is frantic and the commotion is labeled "War Scare?" The birds feathers are broken on a chopping block next to the hut."sketches for cartoon on verso. "Turkey hears a familiar sound."Commotion"More excitement in the coop"Exploitation." Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 11)
    - Nervously awaiting developments., 1926; 1926.0077.Orr; A man labeled "Europe" is standing in the middle of an apiary where the bees are swarming. The hives are labeled "France,"Italy,"England,"Germany,"Balkans,"Poland,"Russia," and "Turkey." In the background, behind a fence, Uncle Sam says to "American Pro-Leaguers,"What was that you were saying about me going in partnership with him?"overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Never felt better in my life, all excepting my hip.", 1926; 1926.0078.Orr; Uncle Sam is standing holding his hip with one hand and the pain emanating is labeled "Bootleg Pains." To his right is an eagle, and to his left is a vase of roses labeled "150th Birthday Greetings." Uncle Sam shakes hands the hand of "The World" with his other hand. "sketches for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 12)
    - The new Uncle Sam., 1926; 1926.0079.Orr; To the right in a room labeled "The National Gov't" Uncle Sam can be seen tied up and labeled "The Old Respectable Uncle Sam." The rope he is tied up with is labeled "Eighteenth Amendment." Walking out of the room in Uncle Sams clothing is a man labeled "The New Uncle Sam - Alias Anti Saloon League." He carries a switch in one hand labeled" Meddling in Local gov't" and a wine opened in the other hand labeled "Volstead Snooping."doodles for cartoon on verso. "The man he used to be." Paper overlay: Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - A New Year's suggestion., 1926; 1926.0080.Orr; Cartoon in two panels: 1. Men are lined in a row with their right hands up all making a different oath: Legislator "- "I resolve to quit passing needless laws!"; "Police" - "I swear to do my duty without fear or favor!"; "Juror" - "I refuse to listen to any more 'Sob' lawyers!"; "Judge" - "I'm going to do all in my power to speed up justice."; "Pardon Board" - "I promise not to break down the law by releasing dangerous criminals!"; "Politician" - "I won't use my influence to help anyone escape justice!" 2. A "Criminal" holds up his right hand in an oath and says "I'm through!" On a bulletin board on the back are the headlines "Murderer hanged,"Gun-man hanged"Killer refused reprieve," and "Auto thief convicted 20 years."sketches for cartoon on verso. "Crime"Congress" Subway"New Years resolutions."Maybe if some of us would make some good use..."Forge" Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - No man's land., 1926; 1926.0081.Orr; A man labeled "Politician who hasn't taken sides is caught between the gunfire of two opposing sides, the "Wets" and the "Drys."sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - No wonder their children haven't any respect them., 1926; 1926.0082.Orr; A large woman labeled "Federal Authority" holds a rolling pin labeled "Bureaucracy" in one hand while she points her finger with the other. Standing across from her is a diminutive man labeled "Hen-pecked state gov'ts." Surrounding them are small children labeled "Law breakers " and "Disrespect for law," who are using their sling shots and throwing spit balls at the two adults. A picture on the wall in the background reads "Home of American politics."is heavily filled with preliminary sketches and writing for cartoon. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Not getting anything., 1926; 1926.0083.Orr; Uncle Sam sits in a chair with a large radio labeled "Negotiations with Europe in front of him." He reads a paper "Station I-O-U. Program Debt Settlement," and says, Those European stations have been awfully quiet here lately." On the floor are paper that say "Unpaid debts," and "Unsatisfactory offers."sketches for cartoon on verso. "Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Not trusting too much to luck., 1926; 1926.0084.Orr; Uncle Sam stands at the end of the gate to the Capitol. He holds in one hand a rabbit's foot labeled "World Court Membership" and thrown over his other shoulder is a large bag labeled "America's Wealth." A man labeled "Congress" walks up to Uncle Sam holding two pistols labeled "Army," and "Navy" and tagged "$660,000,000.00 National defense appropriations" and says, "In case that rabbit's foot doesn't turn out lucky, maybe you'd better take these along."sketches for cartoon on verso. "Pacifism" Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Not trying to dig up John Barleycorn., 1926; 1926.0085.Orr; A man labeled "Modification movement" has a pick over one shoulder as he gets ready to swing at a thorny bush labeled "Graft,"Crime,"Bootlegging," and "The outgrowth of Prohibition." He says, "I've got to get rid of this thorn!" In the foreground is a tombstone in the shape of a barrel labeled "Here lies John Barleycorn." Running towards the man screaming with his hands in the air is a man labeled "Bone Drys."sketches for cartoon with writing on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Now, if everybody will lay down their knives and forks for a moment.", 1926; 1926.0086.Orr; At a table in the foreground is a large cooked turkey labeled "Our blessings" surrounded by men each grabbing at it with their forks and knives. The men are labeled "The 'Help yourself' Spirit of To-day." In the background is a pilgrim with head bowed and hands folded in prayer and the image is labeled "The spirit of Thanksgiving."sketch for unknown drawing on verso. Paper overlay: Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Now if that little rough-neck will only behave....., 1926; 1926.0087.Orr; A man "Father Dearborn" and a woman "Miss Chicago" are getting ready to greet guests into their home for dinner. The father bends down to a small child labeled "Weatherman" and says, "Don't forget your manner now - be a nice boy." Coming through the door are "Our million visitors."doodles for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Nutting time., 1926; 1926.0088.Orr; In the background to the left is Uncle Sam looking up a tree labeled "Europe" with nuts with dollar signs on them. He holds a bag labeled "Debt collection," and he says, "Purty slim pickin's." To the background to the right is a police officer with a bag labeled "The Law" tapping his billy stick on a tree labeled "Bumper Criminal crop." In the foreground is a man labeled "Indiana" who is using a log labeled "Investigation" to ram a tree labeled "Ku Klux Kroud." The nuts are falling from the tree and they're labeled "Political krooks."sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. Torn paper overlay: Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago ....." (Oversize 12)
    - Oliver Twist and Mr. Brumble., 1926; 1926.0089.Orr; A large man labeled "Congress" uncovers a large soup terrine that is in the shape of the U.S. Capitol building and is labeled "Legislation." A young boy with a large girth is on the left and labeled "Eastern States." He drinks from a ladle labeled "Appropriations." To the left is a thin young boy labeled "Mid-West" He holds out his bowl labeled "Needed legislation" and "Farm relief - waterway development," and says, "Please sir! Can I have some --?" Congress has the palm of his hand out as if to stop the thin boy."Brumble: The town beadle who thinks very lowly of Oliver. He eventually marries Mrs. Corney and makes Oliver's life more difficult. Preliminary sketches for cartoon on verso. "The mid-west gets nothing. East gets everything it wants."Control of air" Paper overlay: Reg. U.S.Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - On both sides of the rising issue., 1926 - no date on cartoon, but placed with 1926 cartoons"; 1926.0090.Orr; A man is driving a donkey drawn cart over a draw bridge as it is raising to let a large ship pass underneath. The cart is labeled "Southern democrats" and is caught on the "Dry Issue" side of the bridge. The donkey is labeled "Northern Democrats" and caught on the "Wet" side of the bridge. The large ship passing is labeled "Modification" and it's steam stacks are large bottles labeled "wines" and "beer." (Oversize 12)
    - The only way to overcome the skidding., 1926; 1926.0091.Orr; Two men are in an auto labeled "Temperance Movement" The driver is labeled "Bone drys" and the passenger is labeled "Sane Temperance advocate." The are turning from "Wet Road" onto "Dry Road." The passenger points straight ahead to "Gradual turn toward Prohibtion," and says "Turn 'er back the other way - or you'll wreck us!!"sketches for cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Our most dangerous criminal., 1926; 1926.0092.Orr; The column base of a capitol is labeled "Democratic form of Government." The column is cracking to form the words "Public distrust." The base of the building is labeled "Ballot Box - The foundation of our government" and it has been pried open by a man labeled "vote thief" who has "Stolen votes" in his arms."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Our rich uncle and his poverty stricken son., 1926; 1926.0093.Orr; Uncle Sam is standing next to a barrel labeled "Treasury Surplus" that is filled with money. He drops coins into the barrel. On the ground are papers labeled "U.S. Prosperity," and "World's richest nation." Standing in the background is a soldier from the "U.S. Army" in a "Faded out uniforms," and holding a plate of food labeled "39 cents for daily ration per man."overlay: Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Out in the storm., 1926; 1926.0094.Orr; An elephant labeled "Illinois republican party," is chained in a pen. The elephant is dirty and the mud on the ground is labeled "Investigation disclosures." It is storming outside with the text: Investigation of G.O. P. Primaries," and "Vote fraud probe." A man stands outside the pen with an umbrella labeled "Republican voter." He says as he looks to the elephant, "It'll do him good. He's been needing a bath for a long time!"sketches for unknown cartoon on verso. Paper overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat. Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - The party split., 1926; 1926.0095.Orr; An elephant has been cut in two by a large sword labeled "Brookhart nomination." The front of the elephant is labeled "Anti Brookhart Republicans" and the rear is labeled "Brookhart Republicans." The are in "Iowa" and headed towards "U.S. Senate" following a laughing donkey that is labeled "Democrats."overlay: Reg. U.S. Pat Off.; Copyright, 1926, by The Chicago Tribune." (Oversize 12)
    - Passing the buck to us., 1926; 1926.0096.Orr; Cartoon in two panels: 1. A man labeled "European statesman" is yelling "Forward!" to a soldier labeled "Europe" that is charging with his bayonet. The year is "1914" and Uncle Sam stands on distant shores scratching his head. 2. The year is now "1926" and the "European Statesman" is telling the badly beat up and injured soldier, "He's to blame for all your troubles!" as he points to Uncle Sam."sketches for unknown drawing on verso. (Oversize 12)